Finding Aid for Older Women’s League. Royal Oak Chapter (Mich.) records, 1984-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Older Women’s League. Royal Oak Chapter (Mich.) records 1984-2010
Older Women’s League (U.S.). Royal Oak Chapter (Mich.)
2 linear feet and 2 oversize volumes
2012054 Bk 2
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records (donor no. 10677 ) were collected by Elizabeth A. Dennison and came to the library through Eira Tansey in November 2011.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Royal Oak Chapter of the Older Women’s League was formed March 22, 1984. The chapter dissolved in 2010.
The records of the organization include minutes of meetings, correspondence, newsletters, issue files, scrapbooks, and photograph albums.
Subjects:
Older Women's League (U.S.). Royal Oak Chapter (Mich.); Older women--Michigan.; Women--Michigan--Societies and clubs.; Women's rights--Michigan.; Royal Oak (Mich.)
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Topical Files
  - Activities, Newspaper Articles (includes flyers and ephemera, some related to OWL, all related to aging/elderly issues) (Box 1)
  - Chapter Budget, Minutes, etc., 1998-2001 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, Miscellaneous, mostly 1997-2009, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Dissolution of OWL, 2010 (Box 1)
  - Gray Papers, 1987-1993 (Box 1)
  - Herstory: National: Michigan, 1998-2001 (Box 1)
  - History Month Program, Older Women's Bill of Rights, ca. 1980s-1990s (Box 1)
  - History, scrapbook contents (Box 1)
  - "Hooter" monthly chapter newsletters, 1989-2009, 12 folders (Box 1)
  - Legislative Liaison, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Legislative Liaison Correspondence, 1999-2006 (Box 1)
  - Legislative Liaison Reports, ca. 2006 (Box 1)
  - Materials about Women's history to share at meetings (Box 1)
  - Membership Materials, 1990s-2000s (Box 1)
  - Membership Rosters, Telephone Trees, 1989-2009 (Box 1)
  - Michigan: Bylaws, Historical Narratives-California and Michigan, Michigan items, 2000-2002 (Box 1)
  - Michigan: Miscellaneous, meeting minutes, letters to the national organization re: dissolving the state chapter, 2001-2002 (Box 1)
  - Michigan newsletters, 1988-2002 (Box 1)
  - Mother Day Reports, 1986-2002 (Box 1)
  - National Miscellaneous, 1986-2006 (Box 1)
  - Observer, 1990-2009, undated (Box 1)
  - Older Americans' Mental Health Week, 2006 (Box 1)
  - Reports from Eleanor Mislinay, OWL Legislative Liaison, 1999-2005 (Box 1)
  - Song, 1985, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Women's History Materials, to share (Box 1)
- Albums
  - History, 1984-1999 red album (Box 2)
  - Photographs, 1991-1997 blue album (Box 2)
  - Photographs, 1991-1994 gray album (Volume 1)
  - Photographs, 1995-2008 green album (Volume 2)